The band you know. The story you don't.
The Beatles: Eight Days a Week - The Touring Years is a
documentary, music film directed by Ron Howard.
The Beatles stormed through Europe's music scene in
1963, and, in 1964, they conquered America.
Their groundbreaking world tours changed global youth culture forever and,
arguably, invented mass entertainment as we know it today.
All the while, the group were composing and recording a series of
extraordinarily successful singles and albums.
However the relentless pressure of such unprecedented fame, that in 1966 became
uncontrollable turmoil, led to the decision to stop touring.
In the ensuing years The Beatles were then free to focus on a series
of albums that changed the face of recorded music.
Self, played by Paul McCartney.
Self, played by Ringo Starr.
Self, played by Larry Kane.
Self, played by Whoopi Goldberg.
Self, played by Elvis Costello.
Herself, played by Eddie Izzard.
The Beatles: Eight Days a Week – The Touring Years is a 2016 documentary film directed by Ron Howard about the Beatles' career during their touring
years from 1962 to 1966, from their performances at the Cavern Club in Liverpool to their final concert in San Francisco in 1966.
The film was released theatrically on 15 September 2016 in the United Kingdom and the
United States, and started streaming on Hulu on 17 September 2016.
It received several awards and nominations, including for Best Documentary at the 70th British Academy Film Awards
and the Outstanding Documentary or Nonfiction Special at the 69th Primetime Creative Arts Emmy Awards.